Sam Garg

Hi! I'm a Front-End Web Developer from Sydney with 8 years experience in building small to large-scale multidevice web portals.

I am currently based in Amsterdam and have worked for various agencies and companies around Amsterdam and Sydney - Funda, DigitasLbi (a.k.a Lostboys), Ninemsn (Microsoft). I have also done freelance work for various small-medium sized businesses.

I live and breathe responsive and minimalistic design and am a firm believer of "less is more". I can help you build a brand new website, or make your current site responsive (so it also works on mobile and tablet), as well as help improve its UI, add a Web-Shop, etc.

On a personal front, I am an avid traveller and have explored a lot of places over the last few years. This experience has exposed me to a lot of new people and cultures, which is an asset in today's multi-cultural team environments.

Skills

- HTML(5)
- jQuery
- C# ASP.NET MVC
- Test Driven Development
- CSS(3)
- Knockout.js Umbraco
- Agile Methodologies
- Responsive Web Design
- Demandware
- WordPress
- Kanban
- JavaScript
- Git
- Scrum

Experience

DigitasLBi (Lostboys), Amsterdam

E-Commerce Front-End Lead Developer

- Building web-shop discount marketing campaigns for SCS(Sofas and Carpet Specialist big sofa retailer in the UK with 100+ stores), thereby maximising sales (Up to 400% during Christmas/New Year 2015). Discount sale promotional pods and coupons across the website, 12 hour countdown sales all built using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, SVG.
- Continuously improving the website and web-shop for Vertu global (luxury phones brand from the UK, formerly owned by Nokia), adding new product lines, and promotional campaigns. Multi lingual and a pixel perfect classy UI, design heavy website
- Re-design and built a new fluid pinterest style homepage for Scotch and Soda (a fashion label in Amsterdam).
- Tight deadlines, continuous integration, and a fast changing environment is what we live and breathe

Technologies: HTML5, CSS(SASS), Javascript (Jquery), RequireJS, Grunt, SVG

Funda, Amsterdam

Jul 2013 - Jun 2014

Jul 2014 - Present

Web/Mobile Developer

Funda is the largest online real estate company in Netherlands. http://funda.nl gets about 8 million hits a day. They have a an Agile fast-paced environment with an interesting mix of technologies, mostly Microsoft based, but also some stuff built using Umbraco and Symphony and many other open-source tools.

- · My average day spans across creating new stuff and maintaining existing stuff, while touching a broad spectrum of technologies and frameworks that they use.
- In 2014 I moved to the Mobile team where I was mainly involved in building and maintaining HTML5, CSS and javascript for common web-views that they use across different apps on different devices
- Develop and maintain mobile website http://m.funda.nl

Technologies; HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Jquery, C#.NET, ASP.NET MVC, Knockout.js, SQL Server 2012, Umbraco, Microsoft CRM 2011

Ninemsn (Microsoft MSN), Sydney

Jun 2012 - Jun 2013

Lead Web Developer

I was actively involved in coordinating and developing, conducting daily Kanban stand-ups, mentoring fellow developers and liaising with clients and management. I worked in scrum teams building many projects:

- Leading news portal of Australia http://news.ninemsn.com.au
- A game competition for London Olympics 2012 users score points by sharing articles on their wall and are awarded badges on the basis of points. A leaderboard of highest scores, and at the end the person with the highest score won a car. This was mainly built using the Gigya Javascript API (and JQuery)
- Marketing competitions for Mitre10 and Seek.com.au (HTML5, CSS3, Javascript)
- New website for Australian cooking show Great Australian Bake Off
- · Chartbeat web analytics
- Ad Re-targeting Engine which helped Ninemsn target ads based on user traits.
- Organising company wide Hack day (Hackathon) for 100+ developers, designers and data analysts.

Technologies: Html5, CSS3, Jquery, RequireJS, Gigya, ASP.NET MVC, Sitecore

Ninemsn (Microsoft MSN), Sydney

Aug 2010 - Jul 2012

Software Developer

The Core-Platforms team at Ninemsn is responsible for building and maintaining core CMS systems, databases, Services Framework and Social Platform architecture (Gigya).

- I was actively involved in everything from Design and Architecture, to deployment of several new features built across these products.
- I helped them build and support Gigya social platform from scratch, using Javascript, Jquery and RequireJs.
- I also built an internal Error Logging Framework to log tens of thousands of errors every minute from 80 websites and build reporting on top of it.
- I was also involved in building a Ad Re-targeting Engine which helped Ninemsn target ads based on user traits.

Cloud55, Sydney

Jun 2012 - May 2013

Part Time Co-founder and CTO

A boutique IT consultancy specialising in phone apps and be-spoke web development projects. I am mainly involved in IT Project Management and Sales.

Lucsan Capital, Sydney

Mar 2010 - Aug 2010

Software Developer (Contract)

Lucsan Capital is a small-medium sized firm dealing with data migration for banks and other financial institutions. While I was working there, I was involved in re-factoring and building new features for their in-house data-migration suite written in C# .Net, and SQL Server. I helped them design a WPF based add-in that would auto-generate workflow diagrams showing migration status and other charts.

Adept Business Systems, Sydney

Mar 2008 - Mar 2010

R & D Developer

I was involved in a large scale project including Research, Design and Development, moving a CRM software for Commercial Real-Estate companies, from a legacy desktop Progress Software based platform to a Web Application (now called SurgaCentral). I was also involved in supporting the legacy application from time to time.

Technologies: C# ASP.NET, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Progress

Satyam Computer Services, Sydney

Sep 2006 - Feb 2008

Sales Assistant

At Satyam I was helping APAC's best technology outsourcing sales team. I was assisting the Regional Sales head helping him with number-crunching, sales trends for his team, tracking lost purchase orders and invoices, as well as assist setting up monthly sales meetings. In the first year, I helped them track down and retrieve millions of dollars of lost revenue from their biggest clients in Australia. I was sitting in meetings with managers and senior execs from big companies, which gave me a strong basis to learn and grow in my career.

Education

Demandware
Front-end development in Demandware, E-Commerce/Electronic Commerce

Agile Australia
Agile Project Management - http://courses.scrum.org/about/lachlan-heasman

Sitecore
Sitecore Certified Professional, Sitecore CMS

University of Technology, Sydney
Bachelors of Engineering, Software, Software Engineering